Human Rights Watch records: Record Group 4: Africa Watch 7746709
Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Series 3: Other Country Files, 1985-1997
  - Somalia
    - InterAction: American Council for Voluntary International Action, 1992 (Box 281, Folder 15)
    - International Committee of the Red Cross (ICRC), 1991-1993, 1995 (Box 281, Folder 16)
    - International Freedom of Expression Exchange, 1993 (Box 281, Folder 17)
    - International Organization of Journalists, 1993 (Box 281, Folder 18)
    - Law, 1971 (Box 281, Folder 19)
    - Lawyers Committee for Human Rights (Box 281, Folder 20)
    - Medecins Sans Frontieres USA, Inc., 1993 (Box 281, Folder 21)
    - Media Issues, 1993 (Box 281, Folder 22)
    - Miscellaneous, 1991-1995 (Box 281, Folder 23)
    - Ogaden National Liberation Front (ONLF), 1992-1994 (Box 281, Folder 24)
    - Op Ed/Commentary, 1993 (Box 281, Folder 25)
    - Organization of African Unity, 1991-1992 (Box 281, Folder 26)
    - Overseas Development Council (ODC), 1993 (Box 281, Folder 27)
    - Political Conflicts/Government Policies, 1993-1994 (Box 281, Folder 28)
    - Prisoner Releases, 1989 (Box 281, Folder 29)
    - Publications/Reports, 1994 (Box 281, Folder 30)
    - Reporters Sans Frontieres, 1993 (Box 281, Folder 31)
    - Reports/Briefs, 1991, 1993 (Box 281, Folder 32)
    - Scientists and Human Rights in Somalia, 1988-1989 (Box 281, Folder 33)
    - Somali National Movement, 1989 (Box 281, Folder 34)
    - Somalia News Update, 1993-1994 (Box 281, Folder 35)
    - TransAfrica, 1992 (Box 281, Folder 36)
    - United Nations
      - General, 1992-1993 (Box 281, Folder 37)
      - Mandates, undated (Box 281, Folder 38)
      - Policy Reports, 1993-1994 (Box 281, Folder 39)
      - Security Council, 1992-1994 (Box 281, Folder 40)
      - UNOSOM, 1993 (Box 281, Folder 41)
      - United Somali Congress, 1989-1990 (Box 281, Folder 42)
    - United States
      - Administrative/Executive--Policy, 1992., 1994 (Box 282, Folder 1)
      - Congress--Policy, 1988-1990, 1992-1993 (Box 282, Folder 2)
      - Policy, 1992-1994 (Box 282, Folder 3)
      - U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID), 1991-1995 (Box 282, Folder 4)
      - U.S. General Accounting Office--Reports, 1989, 1994 (Box 282, Folder 5)
    - U.S. Committee for Refugees, 1991-1992 (Box 282, Folder 6)
    - U.S. Institute of Peace, 1992-1993 (Box 282, Folder 7)
    - Women's Issues, 1993 (Box 282, Folder 8)
  - South Africa
    - Domestic Issues, 1994 (Box 282, Folder 9)
    - Economy/Business Relations, 1993-1994 (Box 282, Folder 10)
    - Foreign Aid, 1994 (Box 282, Folder 11)
    - Political Issues, 1993-1994 (Box 282, Folder 12)
    - Press Clippings, 1996 (Box 282, Folder 13)
  - Sudan
    - Behind the Red Line: Political Repression in Sudan--Reactions, 1996 (Box 282, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 282, Folder 15)
    - Op Ed/Commentary, 1993-1994 (Box 282, Folder 16)
    - Political Conflicts/Government Issues, 1993-1994 (Box 282, Folder 17)
    - Press Clippings, 1996 (Box 282, Folder 18)
    - Publications/Reports, 1994 (Box 282, Folder 19)
    - Refugees/Human Rights Issues, 1994 (Box 282, Folder 20)
    - Terrorism, 1993-1994 (Box 282, Folder 21)
  - Togo
    - General, 1993-1994 (Box 282, Folder 22)
    - Publications/Reports, 1993 (Box 282, Folder 23)
  - Uganda
    - Economy/Business Relations, 1993 (Box 282, Folder 24)
    - Press Clippings, 1996 (Box 282, Folder 25)
    - Reports/Publications, 1993 (Box 282, Folder 26)
  - United Nations--Press Clippings, 1996 (Box 282, Folder 27)
  - West Africa--Press Clippings, 1996 (Box 282, Folder 28)
  - Zaire
    - General, 1994 (Box 282, Folder 29)
    - Op Ed/Commentary, 1994 (Box 282, Folder 30)
    - Press Clippings, 1995-1996 (Box 282, Folder 31)
    - Publications/Reports, 1994 (Box 282, Folder 32)
    - Refugees, 1993-1994 (Box 282, Folder 33)
  - Zambia--General, 1994, 1996 (Box 282, Folder 34)
  - Zimbabwe
    - Economic Issues/Business Relations, 1994 (Box 282, Folder 35)
    - General, 1995-1996 (Box 282, Folder 36)
    - Political Issues/Government Policies, 1994 (Box 282, Folder 37)
    - Reports/Publications, 1993-1994 (Box 282, Folder 38)
- Series 4: Liberian Coalition for Relief, Resettlement & Reconstruction, 1979-1992
  In 1989, Liberia experienced a violent civil war. In its aftermath, thousands of Liberians were either internally displaced or became refugees. Established in August 1990, the Liberian Coalition for Relief, Resettlement & Reconstruction (Coalition) sought to address the issues confronting refugees in Liberia and the United States. In October 1990, the Coalition, utilizing space donated by Human Rights Watch (HRW), organized a multi-pronged humanitarian effort that sought to alleviate the suffering of Liberians by shipping food stuffs and medical supplies; engaging in collaborative relief activities with other human rights organizations; addressing refugee issues with Liberian and U.S. officials; hosting fundraising events; and giving lectures to churches, universities and organizations. The series is divided into two subseries: general and subject files.
  - Subseries IV.1: General Files, 1990-1992
    The general files are arranged alphabetically and contain predominantly reference materials such as fact sheets and press clippings.
    - Fact Sheets, 1990 (Box 283, Folder 1)
    - Incorporation Papers, 1990 (Box 283, Folder 2)
    - Press Clippings, 1990-1991 (Box 283, Folder 3)
    - Reference, 1990, 1992 (Box 283, Folder 4)
  - Subseries IV.2: Subject Files, 1979-1992
    Subject files are also arranged alphabetically and comprise correspondence, fundraising documents, publications and reports.
    - Africa Faith & Justice Network, 1989 (Box 283, Folder 5)
    - African-American Institute, 1989-1991 (Box 283, Folder 6)
    - Concert and Fashion Show, 1992 April (Box 283, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1990-1991; (3 Folders) (Box 283, Folder 8 to 10)
      - Camara, Joseph, 1992 (Box 283, Folder 11)
    - Family Tracers, 1990 (Box 283, Folder 12)
    - Fundraising--Documents, 1992 (Box 283, Folder 13)
    - Human Rights Watch Documents, 1991 (Box 283, Folder 14)
    - Liberia Committee for Relief-Resettlement & Reconstruction (LICORE), 1990 (Box 283, Folder 15)
    - Ministry of Education-Revised National Curriculum, 1979 (Box 283, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous Materials, 1990-1991; (2 Folders) (Box 283, Folder 17 to 18)
    - Peace Talks, 1991 (Box 283, Folder 19)
    - Press Clippings, 1990 (Box 283, Folder 20)
    - Press Releases, 1990 (Box 283, Folder 21)
    - Publications/Newspapers, 1991 (Box 283, Folder 22)
    - Refugees and Immigration, 1990 (Box 283, Folder 23)
    - Relief Shipments, 1990 (Box 283, Folder 24)
    - Reports, 1990-1991 (Box 283, Folder 25)
    - Updates, 1990 (Box 283, Folder 26)
    - United States--Aid, 1990 (Box 283, Folder 27)
    - U.S. Committee for Refugees (Box 283, Folder 28)
    - Youth Symposium, 1992 July 26 (Box 283, Folder 29)
- Series 5: Rakiya Omaar Files, 1989-1995
  This series represents Ms. Omaar's work as Executive Director of Africa Watch from 1989-1994. The series is divided into two subseries: general and subject files.
  - Subseries V.1: General Files, 1991-1993
    The general files are arranged alphabetically and contain primarily articles and correspondence.
    - Companies--African Operations, 1993 (Box 284, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence--General, 1991 June (Box 284, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence--General, 1991 July (Box 284, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence--General, 1991 August (Box 284, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence--General, 1991 September (Box 284, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence--General, 1991 October (Box 284, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence--General, 1991 November (Box 284, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence--General, 1991 December (Box 284, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence--General, 1992 January (Box 284, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence--General, 1992 February (Box 284, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence--General, 1992 March (Box 284, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence--General, 1992 March (Box 284, Folder 11A)
      [Restricted until 2067]
    - Correspondence--General, 1992 April (Box 284, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence--General, 1992 May (Box 284, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence--General, 1992 August (Box 284, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence--McGovern, Mary, 1992 (Box 284, Folder 15)
    - Omaar, Rakiya -- Articles, 1990-1992 (Box 284, Folder 16)
    - Omaar, Rakiya --Termination, 1993 (Box 284, Folder 17)
  - Subseries V.2: Subject File, 1989-1995
    Subject files are also arranged alphabetically and include correspondence, memos and monitoring reports.
    - Africa Watch Cables, General, 1989-1990 (Box 285, Folder 1)
    - Africa Watch Correspondence--General, 1990-1995 (Box 285, Folder 2)
    - Africa Watch Memos, 1989-1994 (Box 285, Folder 3)
    - Africa Watch Memos, 1989-1994 (Box 285, Folder 4)
    - Africa Watch Memos, 1989-1994 (Box 285, Folder 4A)
      [Restricted until 2069]
    - Africa Watch Memos, 1989-1994 (Box 285, Folder 5)
    - Africa Watch Memos, 1989-1994 (Box 285, Folder 6)
    - Africa Watch Memos, 1989-1994 (Box 285, Folder 7)
    - Africa Watch Memos, 1989-1994 (Box 285, Folder 8)
    - Africa Watch Memos, 1989-1994 (Box 285, Folder 9)
    - Africa Watch Memos, 1989-1994 (Box 285, Folder 10)
    - Africa Watch Memos, 1989-1994 (Box 285, Folder 11)
    - Africa Watch Memos, 1989-1994 (Box 285, Folder 12)
    - Africa Watch Memos, 1989-1994 (Box 285, Folder 13)
    - Africa Watch Memos, 1989-1994 (Box 285, Folder 14)
      [Restricted until 2024]
    - Africa Watch Memos, 1989-1994 (Box 285, Folder 15)
    - African Commission on Human Rights, 1992-1993 (Box 285, Folder 16)
    - Applications for Visas, 1992-1993 (Box 285, Folder 17)
      [Removed from collection]
    - Monitors, 1995 (Box 285, Folder 18)
    - Monthly, 1989 (Box 285, Folder 19)
- Series 6: Publications, 1990-1991, 1996
  This series contains two publications collected by Human Rights Watch/Africa staff. The first, BBC Monitoring-Summary of World Broadcasts comprises May through December 1991; and January through August and November 1996. The second, Afrique includes runs from May through December 1990; and April through December 1991.
  - BBC Monitoring-Summary of World Broadcasts, 1991 May-December, 1996 January-August, 1996 November; (13 Folders) (Box 286, Folder 1 to 13)
  - Afrique, 1990 May-1990 November; (7 Folders) (Box 287, Folder 1 to 7)
  - Afrique, 1990 December-1991 April; (5 Folders) (Box 288, Folder 1 to 5)
  - Afrique, 1991 May-1991 September; (5 Folders) (Box 289, Folder 1 to 5)
  - Afrique, 1991 October-1991 December; (3 Folders) (Box 290, Folder 1 to 3)